[Music]
yes I am a Tundra teacher today but you
know I I still have my own journey I can
only be the tantric state now then when
I'm in the chunky state I'm very happy
because I get very productive very
creative I get much more caring about
people around me I go into heating mode
I stay away from the conflicts and I can
actually even speak the truth no and
then you know it's people so it's it's
to me to be in the tonic state is to me
as a man 58 years old means I can also
supply the father case for people at
times when they want it you need it I
can only be in that state temporarily I
was always big question I'm only human I
can make the wrong judgments I can rush
to conclusions but I do lot less rushing
to conclusions and I make a lot less
mistakes then a man who'd be younger
than me would do that's because I desire
to be tantric I love being a grown-up
whenever I can I aspire to be an adult
and I consider the current disease of
societies the celebration of the ass
child staying child it's not the
celebration of its child as a human
being on a journey towards adulthood and
eventually a journey towards the
transcendent that's what we need
religion we need a massive return to
religion I'm happy to work with the
Catholics of the Catholic Church as a
philosopher when they get through the
pedophile master currently and right so
once they get through that I think
that's gonna be an interesting place to
work and my mentors are often Catholics
right my mentors the men 78 years old
that I learned from today are often
Catholics I chose to be so Astor because
I want to unify East and West and so
asterism my choice well I just like you
loves option love Buddhism love doe ISM
because I can learn tons of stuff from
these crazy wisdom traditions of beasts
but
we could pick the best not from Eastern
Western we need to be very careful we do
that not jump to conclusions and never
ever be appealed by the instant
gratification like you can get this now
you can get this now you can get this
now which is marketing promises house
marketing says just think this shampoo
in your life will be fine
just pick the soap or just take this
internship contract technique and and
you'll develop this constantly
flattering message the sisters your
finest you are you deserve this now
bullshit I hate marketing
I hate advertising and I think
advertising is rape and I believe the
first thing machine intelligence and
algorithms if he keep the algorithms
clean and pure it's gonna your
advertising it's gonna kill advertising
Falls for my leggings I give speeches in
Europe that I'd like a church them like
tons of money to give the speech the
marketing people say they still don't
get it because otherwise the Winston
listen to me right were they right so
I'm so I'm so having a hard time big
events just because I see how how
intense the marketing motive motive is
everywhere and people on a mask let's
add a third word to turn to tundra crazy
wisdom taken from West supernova what is
the supernova a supernova is an ecstatic
immense over down desperate state before
something implodes everything you see
today in society okay
supernova infantilization the supernova
advertised super Hardy Weiss marketing
and advertising bigger than ever because
it's gone desperate because it's because
it's at its final
its final state and its final state is
Facebook ads and Google ads and that's
exactly we started to hate Facebook and
Google and I can prophesize and tell you
one thing Facebook on what's up and
Instagram we within the next 24 months
they're gonna kill both by just putting
more ads in there mmm-hmm because they
don't get it Facebook is a part of the
old Facebook is not digital Facebook
it's not part of the new paradigm it is
the last
come to the old paradigm to tame and
domesticate the new paradigm to its own
profit motive it doesn't understand the
credibility's everything now Facebook
has no credibility it's an evil company
built on hundreds of psychologists
trying to make us addicted to it making
us children sucking at it called
Facebook and he wanted to scroll on
Facebook 810 hours a day like children
just sucking you know I was thinking
about that when I was using it the other
day is how you always have to go back to
messenger twice you know I hate that I
hate this because this is interesting
because it's like if you if you make
somebody do something in an impulsive
manner whether or not conscious you have
to do it twice it's like creating this
kind of it's creating addiction isn't it
I mean we can call it the Facebook
supernova and because it's so damn you
to so desperate
it will also swallow Watts up an
Instagram meaning get out of those
companies and those brands now mm-hmm
cause we're so tired of them we want
another platform
it doesn't mean Facebook couldn't be
something else it's very unlikely as
long as Zuckerberg sitting there and his
ideologies ruining that game because he
does not understand digital one day
digital is a wall of truth
mm-hmm he's gonna be walki doesn't hit
his head it's a wall of truth or is she
always saying no maybe is that because
it's this kind of the subconscious mind
coming to the surface
yes is that what you mean by a wall of
truth it's like what's hid that's hid
everything that's hidden is is yes
coming up yes that's what you mean yes
that's why I associated with the
Freudian super-ego because the first
traction we're gonna have is that oh my
god all my sins are in the public all my
sins can all be seen that's what the
Machine intelligence will do with us -
well the machines start looking at with
our sensors they're gonna see all our
faults and effect in the gun exposed to
us and that means that since everybody's
human and everybody's faults and defects
we've got to stop believing there's any
perfect role models out there and that's
we have to kill the whole idea that
another person can be wrong for you and
expose the fact that if you want to
teach you be role models only because
you Laci and your infantile and you want
the teacher to be everything you don't
want to be because you want to be lazy
and you want to still in Fatah
you wanna you want to make the
relationship between the teachers have
growing up in you as a child permanent
so you don't have to grow up that's not
the point in teaching the point with
teaching is that the teachers there to
teach you to be a man so that he can die
and go away and you can take over be him
and when you become a teacher you
certainly don't want to be wrong when I
get role model projections on me for my
students god I hate that I do anything
to behave like an asshole when they
project that on me
well I know a teacher I'll tell you a
story who he used to teach in public and
he doesn't anymore and every time he
went in public he would drink a lot of
beer and smoke cigars and yeah really
disgusting anywhere these were from
terrorism and and then when he go back
to it when he go back he didn't even he
wasn't didn't even drink
you know normally he would just put that
on because that's because he because
that's brilliant
I hated the idea of the public you know
looking at him as some kind of refined
spiritual person even though he
obviously quite obviously is or was but
that's what the students are sitting by
the Ganga Singh India jerking off on
their dicks and playing around and just
getting drunk and taking tons of drugs
you know and we trust them because
we can go to them for advice in our
lives because they're suited right
they're the worst because the worst
thing we are the more credible hmm
that's very interesting
that is not infantile behavior at all
that's actually incredibly spiritual no
infant in me ingesting poison to for
liberation or or an outcome alchemic
sense or yes this way I decided not to
children that means I highly respect
admire men who decided to become fathers
no children okay that means I can spend
time not fathering children so I better
spend that time wisely doing things they
could not do so we can create a culture
of mutual admiration between the non
father man and the father man so we can
create a great team you know what then
happens is the ten years down the line
all these guys they decide to the family
raise kids and the great fathers come to
me and ask could you please be my
godfather could it please for the
Godfather this kid and they're like yeah
yeah sure sure like I could be his dirty
nasty uncle that's what I call myself
told these kids to say the first thing I
teach is I'm gonna teach you to love
your father and respect him because it
was young man and did his best once once
you through with that process you can
start looking at me and discover them
your dirty nasty uncle it was too lazy
to have a kid like you but you can still
look at me and go to me to teach you how
to be a full man because I can teach you
the things about manhood your father
never taught you I complement your
father
that's what spiritual teachers do that's
exactly my priest do not have children
that's exactly why they step out of the
reproduction cycle that is the true
meaning of celibacy mother priest it's a
brilliant idea
mm-hmm because then the credible serving
the sons and the daughters oh the
fathers and the mothers in the parish
that is what a good priest does and it
doesn't do the being a fucking role
model
he just said precisely by just being as
much an asshole as the father or the
mother was because when they look at me
and discover that I'm the dirty nasty
uncle I said can you finally start a
spell
your dad cuz he did something really
admire ball haven't done he gave birth
to you negative role model in a sense
like or aura I think I think all perfect
role models are horrible and truly
negative I'm all about you Manning yeah
the person who need best humanity that's
that's the person this that's what you
want to be around the imperfection is
beautiful that's what you learn from Zen
Zen is all about nurturing a culture of
imperfection that's exactly what zan art
is all about a symmetries because if you
look for symmetry which is it's childish
little fantasy that we should max rather
a problem should match everything ever
should be symmetric well the problem is
if everything was symmetric existence
wouldn't exist
he'll be if the amount of antimatter
would match the amount of matter that
wouldn't be universe to begin with you
know if father and mother would be the
same and symmetric what will be the
pointing having father and mother the
whole point would having two different
sides in two different the whole point
would left and right in politics that
they're different but everything is a
symmetric even if you take opposites
there are symmetric and because of your
brain your brain is a symmetric it's
just yes so meaning if you learn as
symmetry in the beauty of a symmetry you
can also learn dialectics dialectics is
precise because these fold do not match
although my mind tries to make the
matter make them symmetric they did not
they're estimating and because they're a
symmetric I can create dialectics which
is what intelligence is that's how you
think so you out of these two you can
great the third and the third is not the
compromise between the two that's a
challenge fantasy no no the third is you
take the anti face as you go back to the
faces and because you can learn from the
face you can go back and take a new look
at the antithesis and from underneath
you can discover a synthesis listen what
we do a religion so the crystalline we
say II Thiessen is just a childish lack
of imagined
nation Richard Dawkins is a boy he's
just it's just unbelievable how much
he's lacking imagination would you
seriously atheism is the end of history
seriously you don't even understand
theism to begin with so to understand
atheism you better go back and try to
understand what you're attacking and
once you understand what religion is
then you can go to the point of a system
in Crete we called synthesis which is
the future religion of the future
metaphysics the new grand narrative that
we have to create oh that's it you're
not a cool thought is that you know the
non-theistic and the theistic traditions
are in a dialectical somehow yeah
exactly they are in the East obviously
because the name God is really the name
we attached to the dead ancestors
because we can attach some credibility
on we cannot attach to the living humans
because they are no longer evolving so
they have lived a full life because I've
lived a full life we can we can point to
them as credible sources for the
credibility of the narrative being told
to us on all we have to move and
progress so so essentially it's the own
father and the or mother
the father of the father or the
patriarch of the patriarch the matric of
the metric are the two stories the
priest tells and then you go to the
priestess that will who's your garden
with us a priest those are the dead
ancestors of the priest that's is that
when you go into the shamanic row and
say you go to Peru and you make the
shameless and you do the shamanic ritual
with them they take you down finally to
the maloca at night and they got all the
skulls of the Dead shaman's there which
is God God is always sin the arm of the
dead goal is always saying they are of
that which has become whole and complete
and therefore can die that is the name
of God
that's what do you think Richard Dawkins
even grasp this remotely
[Music]
he's staking the story of science which
he told to the hunters and the Warriors
in the morning he's mistaken that story
or the mythology which all the tribe in
the evening when the mythology was about
humans moving humans moving from point A
to point B the next day science has
become a mythology that it's too bad for
that science is the story you tell the
hunters in the morning about how human
beings relate to the outside world to
the animals and the plants out there so
you can get food and get something to
eat or if they have to fight another
tribe for territory so so it's just
worse in the hunters have to live in a
very factual reality the tribe that has
the most factual words of factual
hunters will win okay no facts shall
that he arrives with evolution
especially in the Fowler Creon and
that's the real hunters in the Warriors
and fact shall it also rise with the
match our mmm-hmm with a matter of the
oldest woman at the center of the tribe
because she sees the world completely
factually mmm-hmm that's what me toos
mistake was to not to listen to the
older woman because they would have
taught the girls no girls are not
perfect and men are miserable we're all
human no girls make the same mistakes
that boys do I keep coming back to the
same same thing don't we that it's it's
not listening to the the older women and
the older men and especially not to
crazy wisdom because our idea wisdom is
also completely wrong ideal wisdom is
that is a role model that we're just
gonna copy
no we imitate elderly we imitate manners
we don't copy these reading copying
imitation is incredibly important hmm
you cannot copy their own there's no
role model to begin with all human
beings are failures being human is
failure but it's getting up on your feet
and trying again
it's never
to strive for perfection that's what my
whole work is about as a philosopher the
terrible ideas of infinity the terrible
idea is immortality the tell about the
perfection I'm misunderstanding these
are only projections you make on to the
dead so we can have the divine in our
imagination but it does not exist
outside of that imagination
there's no infinity in physics that's
example of modern physics has gone wrong
there are only norma dicen in the
universe
no infinities striving for immortality
just shows that you don't live now it
stretches back to the Big Bang we have a
starting point for the universe there's
no infinity there hmm there's no
infinity I'm totally against the use of
the word of it I think we have to
cleanse language and get it out of there
because I think it's exactly what was
the mistake with West I think we from
the boy Ferris we do Ponte Plato and on
to the courage and on to even up to
Einstein and even max tegmark today all
these guys physicists and philosophers
alike make the mistakes and little boys
they're not grown-up men and they
protect infinity onto the world and it
makes mathematics lacy if you do
mathematics of discovery you bring the
infinity sign to mathematics you can get
around a lot of problems you think you
saw them no you haven't because the
infinity signs you'll never be
introduced to mathematics in the first
place
because of nothing to do in reality
outside of mathematics mm-hmm so this
idea of God is some absolute infinite
potential or no no no God is death God
is that which lived before us and has
died and therefore we can predict on to
God a goal for a journey so that we can
live the journey which is life the point
was never the goal the point was all
direction Moses died before you enter
the promised land what does that teach
us the pointing was his giant the point
was to 40 years the point was to take
one generation out of the you let that
generation
teach a new generation and then die as
we took 40 years before new generation
that didn't have the resentment of life
in Egypt with it walk into the Promised
Land
ultimate Exodus it still is the exodus
is incredibly important our next book is
gonna be on the Exodus you mean as a
mythology directing us towards the
future yeah and that is what the name
God means God God originally starts with
your tribe in my tribe finding out that
our shared different fathers are one and
the same room father we have the same
origin they're the same origin it's my
land and in Jacob have the same father
right okay that is religion the name of
that father ultimate father is gone or
the name of that ultimate mother is God
as the ultimate metric is the universe
planet Earth the cell within which life
can start
that's what master Oracle religion
should be today the original womb and
the womb today called Planet Earth where
we're all little kids swimming around
and we're gonna die we're not gonna be
born we're gonna die on this planet if
you don't save the planet actually the
whole point is that we're never gonna
leave the product
I'm gonna stay on the planet forever you
can't live in outer space yeah why would
you want to leave the planet well you
can you can't that's the whole point why
compare the moon landing with the
building of the pyramids needing the
building Mouse's disastrous mistake we
believe since 1969 we made something
amazing by putting three guys on the
moon no we did not we wasted our
resource on the wrong thing he's
building pyramids again if pyramids were
useless they had no use empty perfected
symbols of death of one little boy's
death meaningless we see the world that
way you then compare the pyramid would
say Japanese Zen isometric art you
certainly prefer the isometric art come
out of Zen in Japan don't you the
pyramid looks really by now doesn't it
well cuz I guess there's a dynamism or a
living force yes
a symmetric dialectical align miss
pyramid is just death yeah death worship
Plato's death worship hot thought of
Hitler's death worship Starling death
worship you know all these fake follows
us would have throughout history false
palaces they think the false messiahs
they're all death worship because the
little boys pretending they can be the
teacher pretending they to be the leader
pretending they could be the chief temp
pretend they could be the priests we
haven't learned a thing and without
being human and that's what they think
they walk in their perfect uniform
costumes like Hitler work in the
uniforms and costumes this is a
plagiarist fantasy about having the
perfect costume perfectly combed hair
and everything is perfect and then you
just look from underneath and you
discover the imperfections you discover
the shit in the pans and this nervous
boy you discover all this nastiness this
balanced everything else around these
perfect little boy Pharaoh's that we had
throughout history and today society's
full of them is full of these little boy
and girl Pharaoh's everywhere full of
themselves young believing they're like
the peak of humanity believing they're
wise to know the world and they know
nothing in their tragic
hmm we live in a very infantilized world
and that that is the real that's the
real cause causality or startle again
that's a real cost sounding of the
problems the reason why the planet is
going down and we have you know climate
disaster is simply because we were all
boys and girls during the individualist
paradigm and we thought the world was
there to be exploited and marketed to
exploitation of marketing two sides of
the same coin that was colonialism and
the ultimate forms of colonialism we
finally solved the dirty of it and the
nastiness of it with Hitler and Stalin
and they territorial expansion dreams
it's always about territorial expansion
who the boys France is always about
territorial expansion but that is so is
it the cost of the neighboring tribe
territorial expansion just that drain
just has to stop we need to go vertical
instead of horizontal
the new phallic dream has to be vertical
instead of horizontal hmmm cuz there's
no turtle left expansion that's why the
moon landing was just pathetic oh yeah
so when you finally colonized into our
planet you went to the moon mm-hmm the
shadow of the earth itself